Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
You know how you
get rid of crabs?
- How?
- You got to shave one testicle.
All the crabs go over
to the other testicle,
you got to light the hair
on fire on that one.
When they all go scurrying out, you take
an ice pick and you fucking stab
- every single last one of them.
The Allied
armed forces have been ordered to
suspend offensive action.
The proclamation of V-J Day
must await upon
the formal signing
of the surrender terms by Japan.
The Japanese
delegation lines up on the opposite side
of the surrender table
from the Alliance.
A war which had entered its
eighth terrible year in China,
which had raged for three years and
nine months for America and Britain,
which was the brutal, costly,
eastern half of the most horrible
worldwide war in human history,
is now within minutes
of ending for good.
General MacArthur speaks.
Let us pray that peace
be now restored to the world,
and that God will
preserve it always.
- These proceedings are closed.
Swarms of
United States aircraft
fly in formation overhead
as the ceremony ends.
The final United Nations
victory has been won.
The war is over, peace is here.
Move it in.
Next table, next table.
Move it in. Move it in.
Move it in.
You men are blessed
with the rejuvenating
powers of youth.
The responsibilities of peacetime
must now be considered.
You can start a business:
filling station,
grocery or hardware store.
Get a few acres of land
and raise some chickens...
...go back to school.
Undoubtedly, there will be
people on the outside
who will not understand
the condition you men have,
or will think it
a rather shameful condition.
If the average civilian
had been through
the same stresses that
you have been through,
undoubtedly they too would have
developed the same nervous conditions.
Freddie, I'm going to show you
a series of pictures.
I want you to tell me the first
thing that comes to your mind.
There's no right or wrong answers.
Tell me what you see.
Well, that's a pussy,
a lady's pussy.
What about this one?
Looks like cock
going inside of a pussy.
All right, let's try it again.
Tell me what you see, Freddie.
That looks like...
That's just like a cock,
actually, upside down.
Thank you.
You've had episodes
of enuresis?
Yes, that's right.
My kidneys were all tore up
from it all over there,
and it came on strong.
And what's this about
a crying episode?
What crying episode?
It says here you had a severe headache,
and a crying spell.
I didn't have a crying spell.
It was brought on by a letter
I received from a girl I knew once.
I think I...
I believe I suffered what,
in your profession,
you call nostalgia.
It was nostalgia that was
brought on by a letter I received.
From your sweetheart?
No, sir, not my sweetheart.
The kid sister of a girl...
The kid sister of a friend of mine
I knew from back home.
I received this letter, and...
I received a letter and I read it.
According to the history here,
I notice that you say
- you saw a vision of your mother.
- Now, it wasn't a vision.
- It was a dream.
- Well, tell me about the dream.
Why?
- I need to know.
- Why do you need to know?
This will help in your treatment.
You can't help in my treatment,
you don't even know...
Well, it was my mother
and my father and me...
...back home.
We were sitting around a table...
...having drinks.
Laughing-
And it just sort of ended there.
Thanks for the help.
Now, you have such pretty eyes,
I want the light to catch it.
Look more this way.
Chin up a little. OK.
And just look at me.
And smile.
- Beautiful.
Ready?
Well, give a good smile.
Three, two, one.
Beautiful.
Only $49.99. Handmade.
Handmade imported mink.
Only $49.99.
Forty-nine, ninety-nine.
- You have a break coming?
- I hope so.
- When?
- Ten minutes.
- Ugh.
- Oh...
- Taste good?
I have an apricot belly,
want to see?
Yes.
I'm really a very good girl.
Where do you get
this idea about me?
Maybe we think the same
things at the same time.
Oh, my goodness.
I think we do.
What else do you
want to see, these?
Yes.
- Are they nice?
- Yes.
- Handmade.
- Yes, they are.
- That's enough now.
- Oh...
Want to go out tonight?
Yeah, sure.
- Are you married?
- Uh, yes.
- This for your wife?
- Pardon me?
- Uh, yes.
Don't move. Just stay still.
It's a little warm.
It's hot.
I'm starting to sweat.
You need to shut up.
You need to move the God...
You need to back off.
Sit down.
I'm very sorry.
I'm trying to get
the lighting right.
You must understand,
I want to get the lighting right.
Oh.
- That's enough.
- Little bit.
Drink that.
One gulp.
- What's your name?
- Frank.
Frank.
You look like my father.
Need some water.
We need to give him some water.
- I didn't put anything in his drink.
- Did you give him poison?
- No, everybody had the same thing.
- No, you're lying.
- I didn't lie, he's dehydrated.
- No, you poisoned him.
- No, I didn't poison him.
- No. He took it, he took it himself.
- No. You poisoned him.
No, he needs some water.
- Move, move.
- No, no, you poisoned him.
- He needs some water.
- You poisoned him, you poisoned him.
Take it easy. Take it easy.
I didn't poison him.
I didn't do anything.
Please take your hands off me.
- I didn't poison him.
- You poisoned him.
I didn't do anything wrong, OK?
He took the drink himself,
he took it.
I didn't do anything.
Good morning.
Are you all right?
Who are you?
Where am I?
You're safe, you're at sea.
Here. Come with me.
Come on.
Here.
All right.
Is this your ship?
I am its commander, yes.
Where is it going?
New York City,
through the canal.
You're a seaman.
Yeah. How did I get down here?
You were acting aggressive
because you drank too much alcohol.
No, I don't think so.
You told me you were an able-bodied
seaman, and you were looking for work.
I told you?
Yeah, well, you have any?
Why all the skulking
and sneaking?
Work cannot be that
difficult to come by.
That depends on when
you're ready to go.
- You shouldn't work in your condition.
- No, I can work.
- You're aberrated.
- No, I'm not.
- Know what that means?
- No.
You've wandered from
the proper path, haven't you?
- These problems you have...
I don't have any problems.
I don't know what I told you,
but if you have work for me to do,
I can do it.
You seem so familiar to me.
Yeah.
What do you do?
I do many, many things.
I am a writer, a doctor,
a nuclear physicist,
a theoretical philosopher...
...but above all I am a man.
A hopelessly inquisitive man,
just like you.
Well, I'm sorry if I got
out of hand last night.
- It was cold and I was...
- Don't apologize. You're a scoundrel.
And as a scientist
and a connoisseur, I have...
...I have no idea the contents
of this remarkable potion.
What's in it?
Secrets.
Can you make more?
Well, not like that.
But I can make you
something different, better.
I'll make something
special for you.
How do you like to feel?
I will give you a full reprieve
from your naughtiness
as a stowaway,
if you make us some more.
I must admit I, I sampled it
and ended up drinking it all.
Would you scrub yourself
and make yourself clean.
My daughter is getting married.
Come and join us.
Leave your worries for a while.
They'll still be there
when you get back.
And your memories aren't invited.
Stand wherever you like.
Good day, good day,
good day, good day.
What a day. What a day.
Mama.
Rascal.
Clark, big day?
- Big day indeed, sir.
- How are you feeling?
I feel pretty well, thank you.
How are you?
Wonderful.
As long as you hold these bodies,
in this life,
you will be man and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
Marriage!
Previous to The Cause
was awful.
Awful.
It was a cycle, like life.
Birth, excitement,
growth, decay, death.
Now... now...
...how about this?
Here it comes... a large dragon.
Teeth...
...blood dripping, red eyes.
What do I got?
A lasso. I whip it up.
I wrap it around its neck,
and I wrestle,
wrestle, wrestle him
to the ground.
I snap up.
I say, "Sit, dragon." Dragon sits.
I say "Stay." Dragon stays.
- Now it's got a leash on it.
I take it for a walk.
And that's where
we're at with it now.
It stays on command.
Next we're going to teach it
to roll over and play dead.
- Love that story.
- So, where are you from?
- Huh?
- Where are you from?
Lynn, Massachusetts.
- Freddie Quell, how do you do?
- I'm Val. I'm his son.
Oh, yeah, I see it.
So what kind of work
will you be doing?
- Not sure.
- Done any Time Hole work?
- Any what?
- Any Time Hole work?
I don't think so.
I don't know what that is.
- I'm sure you're going to love it.
- I hope so.
- Nice to meet you and welcome aboard.
- Looking forward to it.
- How long have you known him?
- Good night!
- About three years.
- Good night, good night, good night.
Thank you, thank you
for being here.
- Norman...
- Three years?
Thank you.
- Good night, Master.
- Good night.
When can we have
some more of your potion?
Whenever you like,
I'll make it.
When I like it,
I'll give you a signal.
I'll rub my nose
and scratch my ear.
What will you need?
- I'll take care of it.
- Good.
- Anything you need.
- Thank you, good night.
Good night, everyone.
Don't get up.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
What a day.
We fought against the day
and we won. We won.
Freddie, feel free to sit with us.
Can you invite him over?
Say, come on over.
Can you say hi?
He's... been writing all night.
You seem to inspire something in him.
- Yeah?
- Mm.
When we're at home, on land,
there's too much pulling him
in each direction.
Every time he sits to write,
a new attack is launched against him,
and he spends too much time
defending himself.
Who's attacking him?
People who are scared.
People who are greedy.
Ex-wives.
That's what's so nice
about being at sea.
- He gets his studies done.
- Hm.
Advances the learning.
He writes book two.
Say "back beyond" and return
to the pre-birth area.
Back beyond,
back beyond, back beyond.
Back beyond.
- How are you feeling?
- Back beyond.
Back beyond... I feel cold.
- Continue, please.
- Back beyond,
back beyond, back beyond.
Continue, please,
and tell me what you hear.
It's my mother.
Recall what she says.
Recall a sound.
It's her voice.
She's saying,
"We shouldn't be doing this,
not while she's inside me."
- Repeat what she says.
- "Not while I'm pregnant."
Repeat what she says.
Do you understand what's happening?
I'm not sure.
We record everything.
Really?
Through all lifetimes.
Man is not an animal.
We are not a pan'
of the animal kingdom.
We sit far above that crowd.
Perched as spirits, not beasts.
You are not ruled by your emotions.
It is not only possible,
it is easily achievable
that we do away
with all negative
emotional impulses,
and bring man back to his
inherent state of perfect.
Man is not an animal.
We are not a pan'
of the animal kingdom.
We sit far above that crowd.
Perched as spirits, not beasts.
You are not ruled
by your emotions.
It is not only possible,
it is easily achievable...
Hm-mm.
Cheers.
Mm.
- Oh, God!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Freddie.
Lovely.
I've been writing.
Feel like I went under.
Dark cloud rolls in, opens up.
Anxious to share new work.
Would you care
for some informal processing?
Sure. What do I have to do?
- Just answer my questions, we talk.
- OK.
Very good. Have a seat.
How are you feeling, Freddie?
Good.
- You rested?
- Yes.
- Excited?
- Yeah.
Have you made some friends?
- Everyone is very nice here.
- Good. Good.
- How are you feeling?
- Yeah, good.
I gather myself.
You'll be my guinea pig
and protégé.
Informal processing.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
Say your name.
- Freddie Quell.
- Say it again.
Freddie Quell.
- Freddie Quell.
- Say it again.
Might as well say it
one more time,
just to make sure
you know who you are.
Freddie Quell.
Are you thoughtless
in your remarks?
I usually put
some thought into them.
Do you linger at bus stations
for pleasure?
No.
Do you get muscle spasms
for no reason?
No.
Do your past failures
bother you?
No.
Do your past failures
bother you?
No.
Do your past failures
bother you?
No.
Do your past failures in life
bother you?
No.
- Is your life a struggle?
- No.
- Do you like to be told what to do?
Is your behavior erratic?
No.
Do you find interest
in other people?
Not really.
- Do you find it easy to be fair?
Yes.
Are you often consumed by envy?
No, about what?
I don't unders...
You mean like jealousy?
- Like jealousy.
- Oh, well, yeah.
I don't like someone else's hands
on my girls.
I don't like to think about it.
It makes me sick.
Are you scientific in your thought?
Yes.
Are you concerned with
the impression you make?
Mm...
I don't understand.
Yes, you do.
Well, most people are asses,
if that's what you mean.
Are you usually truthful to others?
No. I don't know.
- Sometimes.
- Are you unpredictable?
Silly.
Silly animal.
- I couldn't help it.
- Dirty animal.
Sorry.
It's good to laugh
during processing.
Sometimes we forget,
even if it is the sound of an animal.
Freddie Quell, test session,
March 5th, 1950, 1800 hours.
Aboard the sailing vessel Alethia.
LD, MOC, MD,
logged and approved.
Should we sample another sip
before we join them upstairs?
Wait, that's it?
For now.
No, no, no, no.
You got to ask me more.
This is fun.
Come on, you got to ask me more.
Could you answer the next series of
questions without blinking your eyes?
- Yes.
- Without fear and hesitation,
- answer as quickly as you can?
- Sure.
- Again.
Starting now,
you are not to blink.
If you blink we go back
to the start.
Infringement.
You blinked.
Starting now,
you are not to blink.
If you blink,
we go back to the start.
Do you often think about
how inconsequential you are?
No.
Do you believe that God will save you
from your own ridiculousness?
No.
Have you ever had intercourse
with someone inside your family?
Yes.
Have you ever had intercourse
with someone inside your family?
- Yes.
- Who?
- My auntie.
- Have you killed anyone?
- No.
- Maybe?
- Not me.
- Have you killed anyone?
- No.
- How many times did you
- have intercourse with your aunt?
- Three times.
- Where is your aunt now?
- I don't know.
Would you like to have
intercourse with her again?
No.
- Do you regret this?
- No.
- Where is your mother?
- I don't know. Loony...
- Infringement.
- Fuck!
- Back to the start.
- OK.
Do you often think about
how inconsequential you are?
Yes.
- Do you believe that God will save you?
- No.
Have you ever had sex
with a member of your family?
- Yes.
- Are you lying?
- No.
- Who?
- My Auntie Bertha.
- Where is your aunt now?
I don't know, maybe home.
- Are you lying?
- No.
- Are you a liar?
- Yes.
- Have you killed anyone?
- Who?
- Japs in war.
- Do you regret this?
- No.
- What are you running from?
- Maybe I hurt a man, I think.
Maybe he's dead.
I don't know.
- Where?
- In Salinas.
He stole a batch of my booze
and he drank it.
- Is this booze you make poison?
- Not if you drink it smart.
- Are you trying to poison me?
- No.
- Where is your father?
- Dead.
- How did he die?
- Drunk.
Where is your mother?
- Loony bin.
- Is she psychotic?
Yes.
- What is the name of your aunt?
- Bertha.
How did you come to have sex
with your Auntie Bertha?
- I was drunk and she looked good.
- And you did it again and again?
Yes.
Have you ever had bad thoughts
about Master Peggy?
- Yes.
- What did you think?
- I thought you were fools.
- Am I a fool to you?
- No, sir.
- If you were locked in a room
for the rest of your life,
who would be in there with you?
- Doris.
- Who's Doris?
Best girl I ever met.
The girl I'm going to marry one day.
- Is she in Lynn?
- Yes.
- Lynn, Massachusetts?
- Yes, sir.
- Then why aren't you with her?
- I'm an idiot.
- Why aren't you with that lovely girl?
- I got no reason. I'm a fool.
- Do you love Doris?
- Yes.
- Is she the love of your life?
- Yes, sir.
- Then why aren't you with her?
- I don't know.
Yes, you do. Tell me why you're
not with her if you love her so much.
I told her I'd come back,
and I never went back
and now I just,
I got to get back to her.
- Why don't you go back?
- I don't know.
- I don't know!
Close your eyes.
Recall a word.
Flowers.
Can you recall
what you're wearing?
Navy blues.
What do you hear?
Voices inside.
Hello, Mrs. Solstad.
What made you come and see me?
I thought about you.
I thought about you
when I was away.
I got your letter.
They have you write
to soldiers at school?
I wrote to you.
How come you didn't write me back?
I don't know.
I did.
I just... never sent it.
Are you going to Briar Cliff?
I'm not in college.
What are you, a senior?
- Junior?
- No.
- You're not a freshman.
- I'm a sophomore.
- So how old does that make you?
- Sixteen.
- Did you think I was older?
- No.
I don't really remember.
- Can I kiss you?
Recall a sound.
She's singing.
Her voice settles me down.
I'm meant to go to Norway.
- When's this?
- November.
What for?
I'm going to meet
the rest of our family.
Well, I don't think you should go.
No, you're not going to go.
I came all this way to see you,
and I want you to stay here.
All right.
Can you recall a word?
Any word.
Away.
- Say it again.
- Away.
- Who's saying "away"?
- I am.
Outbound for Shanghai!
Need one able-bodied seaman,
one oiler and one baker.
The man McCoughsky.
The man Quell.
- Yeah.
- Oiler?
- Yes, sir.
- Done this before?
- Tomorrow morning, 8:00.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Listen, I gotta go
somewhere for a few months,
so you should go to Norway.
- Where are you going?
- I got a job that takes me away.
- Where?
- I don't know.
Don't ask me so many questions.
I don't know anyway.
You know, I didn't know which window
was yours, and I always guess right.
You take your trip
and come back home,
and that's gonna be our time, right?
That's gonna be our time.
That's gonna be our time, right?
- Yeah.
- Right? Say yes.
- Say yes.
- Yes.
I'll be back in a minute.
Release and return to me.
Open your eyes.
Say your name.
- Freddie Quell.
- Are you here with me in 1950?
Yes.
End of session.
- How do you feel?
- I feel good.
- Left side of your body feel OK?
- Yes.
- Right side of your stomach?
- Headaches?
- A little.
Are you a member of
the Hidden Rulers?
- I don't know what that is.
- Any communist organization?
No.
Any invader force on this
planet or anywhere else?
No, sir.
You are the bravest boy
I've ever met.
To the poison.
Ah.
Well done.
Kools.
I like Kools.
Minty flavor.
Bill!
- Master, hello!
- Hello!
Welcome.
- Welcome back to New York City.
- Thank you.
- We are so happy you're here.
- I'm happy I'm here.
Peggy, watch your step.
Watch your step, everyone.
- Hello, Mildred.
- Hello.
- Nice to see you.
- Mildred.
- Oh, hello.
This is Mildred Drummond.
- Very nice to meet you.
- Wonderful to meet you finally.
- My pleasure.
- And...
The boat was perfect.
- Thank you. Peggy, my wife.
- Hello, Peggy.
Nice to meet you.
And congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Freddie Quell.
- Freddie... Quell.
- Elizabeth, my daughter.
- Yes.
- Hello. How are you?
- Clark, my son-in-law.
- Hello, Clark.
- Lovely to meet you.
- Norman Conrad.
- Yes.
- How do you do?
- Cliff Boyd.
- Good evening.
- Val, my son.
- Oh, yes.
How are you?
I can see the resemblance.
- Yes, yes. So can I.
- Why don't you come with me?
I will introduce you to...
- Oh, well, here's Poppy.
- Poppy!
- Very nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you. Yes.
- And the lovely Brigitte.
- Brigitte!
- Here you are.
- Good evening. Scotch.
- Scotch, OK. Neat or on the rocks?
- Neat.
Neat. Two fingers?
Yeah, it's fine.
- Beautiful.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, Clark. Thank you.
- Would you like something?
- We have some delicious treats inside.
- In the back? Those sandwiches?
- In the back. Yes.
- And an Old Fashioned.
- Old Fashioned for me.
Do you want to stay together
or do you want to come with me?
I'll join you.
All right, come with me, Peggy.
- Thank you so much.
- This is my friend I want you to meet,
- Michelle.
- Hi. How are you?
Open your eyes, come back to me.
What is your name?
Margaret O'Brien.
Well...
Now that you mention it...
...I think I was a man.
Laughing is good.
- My neck feels much better.
- Oh, that's good.
What I just experienced,
was that me?
What was you, darling?
That man in the armor,
was that me?
Yes. That was your spirit.
Our spirits live on
in the whole of time,
exist in many vessels
through time.
This is the vessel
you're existing in now, in 1950.
- Excuse me.
- As you all may recall,
during the trauma that you went through
while we were processing...
Yes.
...It was of the utmost importance
that you experience every detail...
...every specific detail
through all of your senses,
of that memory,
and that we go over it again
and over it again
until it loses its power.
This is very...
- Excuse me.
- This is very important.
- Why it is important...
- Excuse me.
...Is if you bring someone
out of a traumatic event,
back to the present time,
- no matter how carefully you do that...
- Excuse me.
...If you have not
gone over the memory...
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Some of this sounds
quite like hypnosis, is it not?
This is a process of
de-hypnotization, if you will.
Man is asleep. This process
wakes him from his slumber.
I still find it difficult
to see the proof
with regards to past lives
that your movement claims.
Would you care to
submit yourself to processing?
"Look through the telescope,"
as my friend said.
Oh, perhaps another time.
You've also said that these methods,
Cause Methods,
can cure leukemia,
according to your book, and...
Some forms of leukemia.
In being able
to access past lives,
we are able to treat illnesses
that may have started back
thousands, even trillions of years.
- Trillions?
- With a sir.
The earth is not understood
to be more than a few billion years old.
Even the smartest of our current
scientists can be fooled, yes.
- You can understand skepticism...
- Yes!
- ...can you not?
- Yes, yes.
For without it, we'd be positives
and no negatives, therefore zero charge.
- We must have it.
- Good science by definition
allows for more than one opinion,
does it not?
Which is why our gathering
of data is so far-reaching.
Otherwise, you merely have
the will of one man,
which is the basis of cult, is it not?
'Tis, 'tis.
And thankfully, we are, all of us,
working at breakneck speeds
and in unison towards capturing
the mind's fatal flaws
and correcting it back to
its inherent state of perfect.
Whilst righting civilization
and eliminating war and poverty,
and therefore, the atomic threat.
Well...
I find it quite difficult
to comprehend,
or more to the point, believe,
that you believe, sir,
that time travel hypnosis therapy
can bring world peace
and cure cancer.
I have never been
to the pyramids, have you?
- No.
- And yet we know that they are there
because learned men have told us so.
May I ask, what is your name?
- John More.
- Mr. More, if I may,
is there something frightening to you
about The Cause's travels into the past?
- Frightening? No, no.
- Yes.
What scares you so much about
traveling into the past, sir?
- I'm not frightened.
- Are you afraid that we might discover
that our past has been reshapen?
Perverted?
And perhaps what we think
we know of this world
- is false information?
- Time travel does not
frighten me, sir,
because it's not possible.
What does frighten me is the possibility
of some poor soul with leukemia
- coming to you...
- There are dangers
of traveling in and out of time
as we understand it.
But it's not unlike traveling
down a river, you see?
You travel down the river,
'round the bend, look back,
and you cannot see
around the bend can you?
But that does not mean
it is not there, does it?
But certain clubs would like us
to think that a truth,
I say truth, uncovered
should stay hidden.
I belong to no club, and if you're
unwilling to allow any discussion...
No, this isn't a
discussion, it's a grilling.
There's nothing I can do for you
if your mind has been made up.
You seem to know the answers
to your questions. Why do you ask?
I'm sorry you're unwilling
to defend your beliefs
- in any kind of rational...
- If you already
know the answers to your questions,
then why ask, pig fuck?!
We are not helpless.
And we are on a journey
that risks the dark.
If you don't mind,
a good night to you.
Freddie, stop!
This is not the time. Stop.
- And this is where we are at.
At the lowest level to have
to explain ourselves, for what?
For what we do
we have to grovel?
The only way to defend ourselves
is to attack.
If we don't do that, we will lose
every battle that we are engaged in.
We will never dominate
our environment
the way we should
unless we attack.
And this city,
city is just noise.
I know this city.
I know its rotten secrets,
its filthy lies and secrets.
They... invited us here
and welcomed us.
Only to throw us down
and kick us out.
It's a grim joke.
You got the names and information
of the people at this party, right?
- You invited them?
- Yeah, what for?
All right, Clark.
Get up, you're coming with me.
Hey, I need some help. You want to put
on a good show or no? Let's go. Come on.
Yes, who is it?
Mr. More, this is
Freddie Quell from The Cause.
I'd like to have a word.
Mr. Quell,
it's 3:00 in the morning.
Yes, sir, we have a gift
we'd like to present to you.
You'd like to present to me?
How do you... know where I live?
Um, can we come in,
just have a word?
How about if we do it right in
the doorway. How does that sound?
Sure, um...
Shit!
Jesus! Hey!
- Good morning.
Well, I don't think you have
to worry about Mr. John More
speaking out against you.
What did you do?
He had a wise ass mouth.
My little soldier, what did you do?
- You need to tell me so that I know.
- No, I'm not going to tell you.
Nothing bad.
I just...
I just talked to him.
But this is not the way.
Naughty boy, OK?
All right? Freddie?
You are a mischief.
A horrible young man, you are.
This is acting like an animal,
a dirty animal that eats
its own feces when hungry.
We stand far above that crowd.
Don't we?
- Well...
- We need to remember where we've met.
It's nagging at me.
Isn't it you?
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Down, but not out.
No, not dead yet.
- Hello!
Welcome to Philadelphia!
- Everyone all right?
- I'm gonna race you!
You win!
You won, you won.
- Peggy, Elizabeth.
- Hello.
Clark.
When we travel back
in the Time Hole,
there's a different feel
to another period in time
that is so basic
it's hard to describe.
So if you find yourself in a room...
...allow that there may be color
with unfamiliar tones,
perhaps because
the gaslight shining on it.
There may be a strange quality
to the air.
Its particles of dust derive
from un-modern constituents.
Even human bodies seem to radiate
a different kind of warmth
when covered with the fabrics
of another age.
Now, memory filters
all of that out.
But... when we return this way,
the Cause Way,
the way Master has discovered,
everything is intact.
With such gratitude.
Thank you.
What a welcome to Philadelphia.
- I'm in love.
I'm in love.
We've all been in love.
And when we're in love,
we experience pleasure...
...and extreme pain.
And that's what
I'd like to talk about.
"Go Roving."
"Go Roving" in "G."
- Aw...
Sotto voce.
- Everyone!
Yes.
You can do whatever you want...
...as long as I don't find out.
And as long as no one
that I know knows about it.
- Other than that,
stop with this idea.
Put it back in its pants.
It didn't work for them,
and it's not going to work for you.
We have enough problems
as it is, OK?
- Can you come for me?
- Oh, yes.
- Come for me.
...best behavior out.
- Come for me?
- Yes.
- And no more of that boy's hooch.
- No more hooch.
- Say it again.
- Come for me.
Yes. Oh!
Freddie, wake up.
Come on. Wake up.
Come on.
Get yourself up.
- Wake up. Come on.
- Wait.
God. Yeah, come on.
- Come on.
- What's the matter?
Wake up.
Nothing's the matter.
I'm here to help you
with something.
- Wake up. Are you awake?
- I'm up!
- You awake?
- Yes.
- Look at me.
Freddie, I want you to place something
in the future for yourself.
I want you to place something
in the future for yourself
that you would like to have.
And tell me when it's done.
OK.
Now, it's there waiting for you,
and you can go and get it
whenever you're ready.
- Do you understand me?
- Yes.
You can't stay with us any more
unless you quit boozing.
All right.
- Now tell me.
- What?
- Tell me that you will quit boozing.
- I'll quit boozing.
- Say it again.
You know you should wake up, Val.
Your father's speaking,
you might learn something.
He's making all this up
as he goes along.
You don't see that?
I can sleep and wake up
and not have missed one thing.
- You got something to say to me?
- No, sir.
Well, you should have.
You should say something.
Do something.
Say "fuck you." Be a man!
OK, you're all right,
you're fine, you're fine, OK?
Sit down and shut up.
Good afternoon.
Come home. You're late.
It's a beautiful house.
Are you the owner?
- No, sir.
- Is that how your mother said it?
We're looking for
Lancaster Dodd.
- I don't know who that is.
- He's in the house.
- Well, may I come in?
- He's just inside. Yes, come in.
- Now hold on.
- Are you the owner?
No, sir.
Well, I have a civil warrant here
- for a Lancaster Dodd.
- You're late.
Release and return
to present time.
- Excuse me, Kim.
- The owner's in the house.
May I come in?
No, you can't.
We're gonna have to talk to...
- He's just inside.
- I have a warrant here
to serve Lancaster Dodd.
A civil warrant.
What's happening here?
Good afternoon.
Are you Lancaster Dodd?
Good afternoon. Yes, I am.
I have a warrant
for your arrest, sir.
Goody. What are the charges?
By the district court
of Pennsylvania,
The Mildred Drummond Foundation
for wrongful withdrawal of funds.
This is a silly joke, no?
- No, it isn't, sir.
- This is...
I have to take you in
and book and fingerprint you.
...comic opera.
Is it illegal in this city
to get better?
No, but it's illegal to operate
a medical school without a license.
This is not a medical school,
it's a house.
Sir, this is my home
and these are my guests.
Ma'am, this is the City of
Philadelphia Police Department.
We have no disagreement with these boys
doing their work and all its silliness
as defenders of what code?
Well, we're with the City of
Philadelphia Police Department.
- What honor?! What honor do you have?!
- State of Pennsylvania, sir.
- Put your hands behind your back.
- What part of the galaxy...?
This is a scientific gathering.
Freddie! No, no, no, no, no.
- Calm down!
- No! Freddie!
Freddie! Calm down! No!
Calm down!
Do not hurt him!
Freddie!
It'll be OK!
Please, don't hurt him!
- I am with you, Daddy.
- You'll be out in no time.
We'll be...
we'll be out shortly!
- Just laugh!
- Just laugh.
- Everyone's laughing.
- Not you.
- I'll bring him to the station.
We're following right behind.
We'll be right there.
- OK. I'm fine. I'm fine. OK.
- We're following right behind you.
I'm with you, Daddy.
I'm fine. I love you!
Love you, too!
Your fear of capture
and imprisonment
is an implant from
millions of years ago.
This battle has been with you
from before you know.
This is not you.
- Shut the fuck up!
- It's not you.
- You are asleep.
Your spirit was free...
...moving from body
to the next body, free...
Free for a moment.
Then it was captured
by an invader force
bent on turning you
to the darkest way.
You've been implanted
with a push-pull mechanism
that keeps you fearful of
authority and destructive.
We are in the middle of a battle
that's a trillion years in the making,
- and it's bigger than the both of us.
- You're making this shit up!
You make this shit up!
You don't know what
you're talking about.
I don't know what
I'm talking about?
No, you don't.
I give you facts.
- You don't give me facts!
- They are not opinions.
- What facts? What facts?
- They are fucking facts!
- Fuck you!
- Fuck you! Fuck you!
- Why don't you kick the bed some more?
- Fuck you!
- Fuck you, you lazy ass piece of shit!
- Fuck you. Fuck you.
- I'm not lazy!
- I'm done!
- You're fucking lazy!
- Oh, you make shit up...
- You're fuckin' lazy!
- Your fucking family hates you!
- Your son hates you!
- Oh, they do?
- Yeah! Your son hates you.
- Who fucking likes you except for me?
- Nobody!
- Except for me.
- No, you don't fucking like me.
- Who likes you except for me?
Shut up!
- Except for me?
- You, shut up!
- I'm the only one who likes you.
- Fuck you!
- Fuck you, too!
Fuck you!
- Just me, Freddie.
- Just you?
I'm the only one that likes you.
The only one.
You're a fucking drunk.
And I'm done with you.
Fucking...
- Mr. Dodd?
- Yes?
You're hereby ordered
to pay back $11,000
to the Mildred Drummond Foundation
no later than June first,
otherwise to incur
penalties of interest.
There's also the matter of
$1,500 in fuel and damages
to Mrs. Drummond's sailing yacht,
that shall be repaid on the same date.
- Dad?
- Yes?
I don't think Freddie's as committed
to The Cause as The Cause is to him.
When I told Freddie about
your unpublished work...
...his question to me was...
... "What is something like that worth?"
I think Freddie Quell's a spy.
Perhaps working
for some outside agency,
or the man's working for himself.
To steal and sell your book
to any dissenters who may want it.
"How do we know who he is?"
is perhaps the question.
And "What is the reason
he is here if he is past help?"
He makes me nervous.
I think he wants me.
I think he's in love with me.
I wonder how he got here,
and what he's after.
Is it really all so easy
that he just came across us?
He's a drunk,
and he's dangerous.
And he will be our undoing
if we continue to have him here.
Thank you...
...all of you...
...for your honesty.
But...
...if we are not helping him,
then it is we
who have failed him.
'Tis it not?
Perhaps he's past help.
Or insane.
Thank you, truly.
Thank you.
Food for thought.
There you go.
Oh! Almost.
Freddie, stand in the middle
of the room, please.
Pick a spot over there,
touch it, and describe it to me.
Um... It's wood, wall.
Fine, fine.
Walk to this window over here.
Touch a spot on the window
and describe it to me.
It just feels like glass.
Well, that's because it is glass.
Describe it.
Describe it the best you can.
- Well, it's smooth.
- Right.
It's warm, warmer than the wood,
because the sun's coming through.
Very good.
Very good. Now, walk to
that wall again, touch a spot.
Close your eyes.
This exercise will help
you with your concentration.
What color are my eyes?
Green.
Turn them blue.
A Ferris wheel?
That's beautiful. Back again.
Faster, please.
Ooh.
Could we move that back?
- It's a fucking wall!
- Could we move that back, please?
I feel it! It's wood!
Turn them black.
What color are my eyes?
Black.
Very good.
What we will do now
will urge you toward existence
within a group,
society or family.
This is called Application 45,
Version 1.
No matter what is said between
the subjects, we do not react.
- OK.
- No matter what is said.
And you must look at the subject.
You must look at the subject.
All right?
One minute.
Clark, you may begin.
Doris.
- Fail.
- Are you fucking kidding me?
Fail.
It's the same fucking wall.
Nothing. Nothing.
That's what I feel, nothing.
All right.
Lunch on the veranda today.
So, if you could all move,
except for you, Freddie.
Back again, please?
Everyone.
Beautiful day.
Well, luckily, I don't care.
- Doris, Doris, Doris, Doris, Doris.
- Doris.
See, it doesn't even affect me.
Doris. Say it.
- Doris.
- Doris, see?
- You miss her?
- Huh?
Do you miss Doris?
Say her fucking name again,
I swear to God.
- Doris.
- I swear to fucking God!
Doris.
Doris, Doris, Doris.
This is difficult for you.
Listen.
"'It's really a damn shame to tease you
so, my little whore, he laughed,
'So, I will get the dildo
out of my cabinet in the next room.'
He was scarcely gone many
seconds before he returned,
and I felt his fingers
opening the lips of my cunt.
'Oh, oh, who is that?'
I screamed from under my skirt."
I don't want to hear any of this.
Just listen. No reaction.
"Kiss her. Put your tongue
in her mouth, my boy.
Fuck, fuck, fuck away."
Rocks, covered in moss.
Fields, running around,
barbed wire.
Open, storm...
Apples. Daddy, can you
pass the apples, please?
Cold, out at night.
Meadow... open.
Back again!
- It's a hard, slow process.
- I just don't understand it.
I don't either.
That's why we're here.
Do not do that, please?
Resume the exercise,
no matter what is said.
- What?
- You may talk to Clark.
One minute.
Whatever comes to your mind.
True or false.
I don't want to say anything.
Then don't say anything.
Just look at him. One minute.
Starting now.
I want to fart in your face.
I wish I could fart.
Because I'd fart in your face right now.
Um...
Wallpaper.
I don't know,
this is getting really hard.
OK, all right.
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
I don't know.
How is this helping?
You'll see.
Doris.
She got rid of you, right?
She saw you for what you are:
selfish and alone.
You should go into the hospital
with your mother,
because that's where you belong.
Because you're sick,
and you're tired,
and you need to be alone,
away from people.
How many people
you kill, dummy?
Are you drunk, dummy?
Did you blow them all up
and burn them?
Dummy, dummy, dummy.
Can you stay still, dummy?
Can you, dum-dum?
Are you a loser?
You lunkhead.
Fail.
- But...
- Fail.
Mannequin...
It's a fucking wall!
It's a fucking wall.
And I'm not in it.
I'm not in it. It's a window
and I can leave any time I want.
But I choose not to.
I choose to stay here.
It's breathing.
No matter what is said,
we do not react.
Freddie, you may begin.
I was on a ship that got
13 battle stars and won the war.
What'd you do, dummy?
I can feel outside,
I can touch the neighbor's house.
I can touch the plants,
I can touch the stars,
I can touch anything I want.
And end of Application.
- You're fucking with me.
- End of Application.
- Freddie, open your eyes.
- It's a fucking wall!
Open your eyes
and come back to me.
Very good.
I am here to announce the first
Universal Congress of The Cause
to be held May 21st, 1950,
in Phoenix, Arizona,
a city named
for that glorious bird,
whose resurrection
from the ashes fits our own.
And it is here we will
present Book II.
What's in it?
My unpublished work.
My life's work.
Hold on. Hold on.
All right.
Please, come and join us.
Please, come get insight on
how to be freer, more productive,
and more in command of your life.
- Free yourself, ma'am.
- Don't...
Free yourself from past trauma.
Take command of your life, sir.
Would you care for
some free processing?
Sir, would you care for some
free processing? It's free.
Free yourself from past traumas.
Free yourself from past trauma.
Take control of your life.
Free yourself
from your ailments.
Free yourself from your ailments.
Take control of your life, sir.
Take control of your life.
You don't have to
change your faith
or leave the congregation
you belong to.
So those interested in freedom
are urged to please come
for free sample processing sessions
in being younger, feeling freer,
and understanding
where you come from.
It works.
I added that.
- OK, ready?
- Is it in focus?
I was just asking.
- Go ahead, snap away.
- OK.
Ready?
One, two...
Thank you.
Hi, Helen.
It's almost here.
That's enough.
That's enough now.
You're gonna make me
red all over.
Thank you. Thank you.
Book II... is about man.
And the title of the book
is The Split Saber.
And here we have some answers.
No more secrets.
The source of all creation...
...good and evil...
...and the source of all...
...now, funny enough,
the source of all...
...is you.
I have unlocked...
and discovered
a secret to living
in these bodies that we hold.
And, oh yes, it's very, very,
- VERY, VERY SERIOUS.
The secret...
...is laughter.
Now, I'd like to discuss
processing and communication.
The art of listening,
if you will.
Bill.
Hello.
- How are you?
- Fine, thank you.
- You came from New York?
- New York City, yes.
So, what do you think
of the book?
What do you think about it?
I think it stinks.
If it were up to me I'd chop this thing
down to a three-page pamphlet
and hand it to people
before they got on the subway.
But I edited most of
his earlier work.
Can I talk to you for a minute?
- Outside?
- Let me say this,
the man is a grade-A mystic.
A true, original mystic
of the highest order.
But his work is garbled and twisted,
and let me tell you...
What... What is this?
- Hello.
- Helen.
- Author.
- Please.
- I've been reading the new book.
- What do you think?
I think it's wonderful.
- Wait till you get to the good parts.
- Oh, yes.
Well, as I've begun, I did notice
on page 13 there's a change.
You've changed the
processing-platform question.
Now it says,
"Can you imagine...?"
Yes.
If our previous method was to induce
memory by asking, "Can you recall,"
doesn't it then change everything
if now we say, "Can you imagine?"
We are invoking a new, wider range
to account for the new data.
"Can you imagine," allows for a more
creative pathway to the mind.
More open.
- But if the new...
- What do you want?!
Helen.
This is the new work.
Over here!
The game is called
Pick-a-Point.
You pick a point, drive straight at it,
as fast as you can.
I'll go first.
I pick that winding road.
Good job, Daddy!
Ya-hoo!
Whoo!
Whoo-hoo!
Thrilling!
- Thrilling.
Freddie.
Pick a point.
Tell it to me.
The rock...
The mountain.
The head.
It's the head of an alligator.
Good.
Whoo! Freddie!
Go, Freddie!
He's going very fast.
- Good boy.
Freddie!
- Hello?
Hello?
Mrs. Solstad,
I'm looking for Doris.
Oh.
- What for?
- Because I'm looking for her,
because I want to talk to her.
That's what for.
Well, Doris is in Alabama right now.
- What's she doing in Alabama?
- Well, she's there with, um... Jim Day.
They're married. He's in ROTC
training, Navy flight training.
- Jim Day?
- Mm-hm.
- Jim Day, Jim Day, that Jim Day?
- Yes.
- Jim Day from Somerville.
- Well, when'd that happen?
They've been married
for three years.
Is he still ugly?
She has two children.
Boys or girls?
Two boys.
Are you coming back home?
No, I was just visiting.
I thought I'd see
if she was around, say hello.
How's your family doing?
Yeah, all right.
Well, she's not here.
You could write her.
I have an address.
I'm not gonna
write her a letter.
All right.
Was she upset last time I was here?
When I left her here?
- Yes.
- Was she broken up about it?
Yes.
- She told you what happened?
- Mm. Yeah.
What'd she say?
That you said that
you'd come back sometime.
Is that right?
It was a long time ago.
Where have you been?
I been working.
Working, traveling.
I think I've been halfway around
the world since I last saw Doris.
How old is she now?
Doris is 23.
'Cause I wanted to know.
You know, she was...
She was too young when I...
Well, she's happy,
and that's good.
I'll tell her you came to see me.
Ah, that's not gonna matter.
Give me a break.
It was nice to see you.
Am I leaving?
No. Whatever you'd like.
You can come in.
- Nah. I gotta go.
- OK.
Thank you.
- How's Mr. Solstad?
- Why, he's very good.
He's working, and...
- Will you tell him I said hello?
- All right.
So, her name is Doris Day?
Like the Doris Day?
Yes.
- The movie star.
- Yes.
Who are you?
My name is Casper.
Hey, Casper.
Would you like to play pirate with me?
Oh, boy! Would I!
How are we gonna
tie this together, Casper?
I found some rope.
Gee, Casper,
you're a tricky one.
Hello?
I miss you.
How'd you find me?
We're tied together.
Who got to you, Freddie?
- What?
- Who got to you?
Nobody.
Come to England.
You'll love it here.
Andi think it'll do you some good.
Can you do it?
- Where?
- We have a new school. It's in England.
Well, my spaceship's in the shop.
You've still got it.
Would you bring me some Kools?
They don't have them there?
The only bad pan'
over here, no Kools.
How'd you find me?
Freddie, I have a matter
of such urgency,
a matter that only you
can help me with.
That may, in fact, cure
the insane once and for all.
I can cure you.
And I remember where we've met.
- Come to England. I'll tell you.
Now, for the treasure!
"X" marks the spot
where the sunken treasure is.
Golly, Billy, there's the "X."
I'll get the treasure, Casper.
The captain never
leaves the ship. I'll get it.
Hello. Welcome.
Can we help you and
invite you to sit down?
You look like
you've traveled here.
- How else do you get someplace?
- Can I assist you in help?
- I'm here to see Master.
- And what's your name?
- Freddie Quell.
- Is he expecting you?
- He should be.
I took that picture.
Hello, Freddie.
Val.
You look good.
Come on.
- Can I get this for you?
- No, thank you.
- How are you?
- Couldn't be better.
Hello.
Hi.
Thank you.
Some place.
Are you drunk?
No. No, no.
You look sick.
Freddie, you don't look healthy.
I don't look like that.
That's not how I look.
You don't think you can?
It's just not how I look.
You can't take this life straight,
can you?
What do you want?
I don't know.
I had a dream...
Where's Elizabeth?
- DCF.
- Really? What is that?
What did you expect
would happen coming here?
I can take pictures...
...if you need them.
We don't need pictures, Freddie.
This is something you do
for a billion years or not at all.
This isn't fashion.
This is pointless.
He isn't interested
in getting better.
She's really softened up.
Free winds
and no tyranny for you?
Freddie...
...sailor of the seas.
You pay no rent.
Free to go where you please.
Then go.
Go to that landless latitude,
and good luck.
For if you figure a way to live
without serving a master...
...any master...
...then let the rest us know,
will you?
For you'd be the first person
in the history of the world.
In my dream, you said you'd...
you figured out where we met.
I went back and I found it.
I recalled you and I working together...
...in Paris.
We were members
of the Pigeon Post.
During a four and a half month siege
of the city by Prussian forces.
We worked and rigged balloons...
...that delivered mail
and secret messages...
...across the communications blockade,
set up by the Prussians.
We sent 65 unguided mail balloons
and only two went missing.
In the worst winter on record.
Two.
If you leave here,
I don't ever want to see you again.
Or you can stay.
Maybe in the next life?
If we meet again
in the next life,
you will be my sworn enemy,
and I will show you no mercy.
Do you think you could just
look into my eyes and not blink,
and I'm gonna ask you some
questions that'll help you?
Maybe.
All right. Starting now.
You can't blink.
You just look in my eyes.
- You're already blinking.
Starting now, all right?
What's your name?
- I told you...
- No, just say your name.
You don't remember?
- Just say your name.
- You're drunk.
You have to say your name.
And you blinked,
infringement, back to the start.
Now, say your name.
Winn.
- Now say your full name.
- Winn Manchester.
- Say it again.
- Now, say it again.
- Winn Manchester.
Have you ever lived before?
I don't know.
Maybe this isn't your only life.
- I hope it isn't.
You're the bravest girl
I've ever known.
Now stick it back in,
it fell out.
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.OpenSubtitles.org